KRISTIAN SMITH

Raleigh, NC

Phone: 919-889-3182 | Email: krissmithcodes@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/kristiansmith220 | **GitHub**: https://github.com/KrisSmith7 | **Portfolio**: https://tinyurl.com/krissmithcodes

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for impactful visuals, user-friendly applications, and intuitive experiences. Effective problem solver and creative thinker with strong organizational and analytical skills. Known amongst staff for adaptability, fast-paced learning, and collaboration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, JavaScript, React, Handlebars.js

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, NoSQL, Sequelize ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM **Concepts:** APIs, REST, MVC, TDD, JSON, RegEx, Big O Notation, Progressive Web Applications

Tools: Git, Github, Heroku, VS Code, Bcrypt

PROJECTS

Social Rolls | **Github** - https://github.com/KrisSmith7/roll-initiative | **Application** - https://socialrolls.herokuapp.com/

- **Social Rolls** is an application that allows Dungeons and Dragons enthusiasts to share posts in a forum with other users, store their character sheets, and offers a resource for beginners to learn about the world of DnD.
- Styled application using Tailwind, Fetched and rendered Third-Party API data to page, Worked in a 4-person team to create an MVP quickly without sacrificing code quality
- Tools / languages used: Javascript, React, Tailwind, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, MongoDB

Media Gems | GitHub - https://github.com/KrisSmith7/media-gems | **Application -** https://gentle-dusk-15958.herokuapp.com/

- Media Gems is an application that allows authenticated users to post and view reviews for popular shows/movies available on a variety of streaming services.
- Created views for the application using Handlebars.js, used Node.js and Express.js to create a RESTful API
- Tools / languages used: Javascript, MySQL, Bcrypt, Handlebars, Express.js, Tailwind

EXPERIENCE

Patient Coordinator Main Street Family Dentistry

2019 – 2022

Holly Springs, NC

- Demonstrated efficiency, collaboration, and task management in a remote environment
- Exhibited high emotional intelligence: active listening skills when resolving patient conflicts, managing pressure while helping others feel at ease
- Utilized effective communication skills in communicating complex financial agreements and insurance claims
- Used critical thinking and resourcefulness to foster efficient posting processes allowing accounting times to be drastically reduced

Key Accomplishments:

• Implemented new medical billing program and created training materials for the practice

Assistant Center Manager

2016 - 2019Baby + Co Cary, NC

- Promoted birth center and nurse-midwifery mission to public
- Streamlined internal processes to improve center/management efficiency and client experience
- Managed ongoing client retention and assisted in growth of pipeline by 50%
- Developed strong interpersonal relationships with staff, families, and other health care professionals
- Operated multiple technology systems

Office Manager

2015 - 2016 Raleigh, NC

Riccobene Associates Family Dentistry

- Oversaw office staff of 8 to ensure efficient and compliant operations in the practice
- Responded to doctor, patient, and employee concerns and inquiries
- Generated and analyzed regular financial, insurance, and production reports
- Reviewed and approved invoices for office materials, medications, and lab cases
- Led patient reception and maintained confidential patient records
- Processed insurance claims/disputes and billing transactions for patients
- Hired new reception staff

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina A 24-week intensive program - curriculum consists of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, progressive web apps, agile methodology, computer science, database theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Git

UX/UI Certificates: Google via Coursera

- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design foundational concepts in UX design, such as usercentered design, the design process, accessibility, and equity-focused design
- Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate focus on common UX research methods, understand their needs and pain points, develop problem statements to define user need, generate ideas for possible solutions to user problems

Bachelor of Arts: Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA